Guide to the George and Grace Snyder Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
George and Grace Snyder Papers
1917-1982
RG 160
Yale University Divinity School Library
2.5
(5 boxes)
Correspondence and printed material document the work of the Evangelical and Reformed Church China mission. George and Grace Snyder were American missionaries in Yuanling, Hunan Province, China, serving under the Evangelical and Reformed Church from 1920 to 1950.
Snyder, George Randolph, 1895-
Snyder, Grace
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from New York offices of United Church Board for World Ministries, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
George and Grace Snyder were appointed as missionaries to China serving under the Evangelical and Reformed Church in 1920. Grace Snyder received B.A. and D.D. degrees from Wooster College and an M.A. degree from Columbia University. She was teacher and treasurer of Eastview School in Yuanling, Hunan Province. George Snyder graduated from Heidelberg College and the Dayton Theological Seminary and also received an M.A. from Columbia University. He served as executive secretary for the Hunan Church of Christ in China.
Scope and Contents
This collection provides valuable documentation of the Evangelical and Reformed Church mission in China, particularly in Hunan Province. Series I, Family Correspondence, contains regular, detailed letters dating from 1926 to 1954. This correspondence is complemented by the Mission Board Correspondence of Series II, and General Correspondence in Series III. George Snyder was a mission administrator who carefully documented and reported his work to the Evangelical and Reformed Mission Board. The minutes and reports of Series IV reflect this careful documentation and reporting. Six diary volumes in Series V and a small amount of writings by Snyder in Series VI supplement the available correspondence and reports. The Collected Material of Series VII includes material related to the Abounding Grace Hospital. The Photographs of Series VIII include portraits of Snyder as well as Chinese and Western colleagues and friends.
Arrangement
I. Family Correspondence
II. Mission Board Correspondence
III. General Correspondence
IV. Mission Minutes and Reports
V. Diaries
VI. Writings
VII. Collected Material
VIII. Photographs
Missions -- China; Missionaries; Snyder, George Randolph, 1895-; Snyder, Grace; Evangelical and Reformed Church
- Family Correspondence, Series I
  - Letters, 1926-1954, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
- Mission Board Correspondence, Series II
  - Snyders to/from Evangelical and Reformed Mission Board, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Snyders to/from Evangelical and Reformed Mission Board, 1941-1948 (Box 2, Folder 14-21)
  - Snyders to/from Evangelical and Reformed Mission Board, 1951-1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- General correspondence, Series III
  - A - E (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - F - I (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - J - P (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - S - W (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Circular Letters of Snyder, 1933-1948 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Evangelical and Reformed Mission Board Minutes and Reports, Series IV
  - Minutes
    - Minutes, 1939-1950 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
  - Reports of Board, by Snyder
    - Reports, 1919-1954 (Box 2, Folder 31-34)
  - Reports of Board
    - Reports, 1927-1966, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
  - Minutes of China Mission
    - Minutes, 1917-1947 (Box 3, Folder 37-40)
- Diaries, Series V
  - Two volumes, 1928,1937 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Four volumes, 1938,1941 1945,1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Writings of Snyder, Series VI
  - Sermons and Slide shows (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Notes (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Collected Material, Series VII
  - Abounding Grace Hospital (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Letters to Europe and America from Chinese students; Maps (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - China Mission (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Photographs, Series VIII
  - Chinese (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Negatives (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
  - Negatives (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Snyders, including with staff members of seminary, 1958, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Western (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Buildings and scenery (Box 5, Folder 55)